Patrick A. Levell

home 519.641.7529 • email patrick.a.levell@gmail.com

Profile

Results-driven Computer Systems Analyst / Developer with broad-based experience in enhancing system functionality and end-user productivity. Accomplished professional who has earned a reputation for consistently meeting and exceeding aggressive objectives. Effective communicator possessing excellent interpersonal and relationship-building skills.

Computer Skills

System Software

Applications

Development Tools

- > JD Edwards EnterpriseOne, > WordPress OneWorld Xe ERP
 - MS Word, Excel, Visio > MS Publisher
- (SSAS, SSIS, SSRS) Visual Studio

- Windows XP/2008
- > MS PowerPoint

- IIS/FrontPage
- > Pages, Numbers, Keynote
- > SharePoint Designer Crystal Reports

> SQL Server 2005/2008

- Ubuntu/Debian Linux > Apache
- > OpenOffice / LibreOffice
- Qt Creator

Professional Experience

The Raymond Corporation, Greene, New York

2007 to 2012

Programmer / Analyst

- > Working closely with executives, consultants, customers, suppliers, and end-users to define and refine requirements for Raymond's IT infrastructure
- > Developing, designing, implementing, testing and maintaining the iWarehouse® Fleet Optimization System, Raymond's first commercial software offering
- > Supervising consultants and junior programmers working on a variety of projects
- > Monitoring and troubleshooting issues in J.D. Edwards, data warehouse, and iWarehouse
- > Developing strategy for streamlining operations by integrating business processes
- > Using J.D. Edwards EnterpriseOne ERP forms and reports in combination with VB.Net and SQL Reporting Services in delivering optimized business solutions for National Accounts, Sales & Marketing, Warranty Services, and the Raymond dealer network

NUCOR Vulcraft - Florence, Florence, South Carolina

1997 to 2007

Computer Systems Analyst / Developer

- > Designing, developing, implementing, testing, and maintaining custom applications and reports in J.D. Edwards OneWorld ERP/MRP for Engineering, EMS/QMS, and other business systems
- > Developing specialized reports & applications with J.D.Edwards, SQL gueries, Excel, Access and VB/VB.Net/SQL Server
- > Working closely with users in defining & "fine tuning" requirements & creating documentation
- > Training and supporting JD Edwards users in Finance, MRP, Sales, Purchasing, and Inventory modules

Krolman Inc., Toronto, Ontario

1995 to 1997

Contract Windows Programmer

> Designing, developing, testing, and maintaining custom CRM application using Borland C++, Paradox and ObjectPAL.

Education

DeVry Institute of Technology, Chicago, Illinois

1995

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems Cumulative GPA 3.62 (Honours)

Integrated ERP Project Highlights

Custom applications with components in multiple environments, including JD Edwards EnterpriseOne and SQL Server, as follows:

- > iWarehouse Gateway—a web application for fleet management and optimization; modules include the following:
 - iImpact impact monitoring (asset protection)
 - o iMetrics vehicle and operator utilization
 - iVerify operator checklist monitoring
 - o iBattery battery utilization
- > Capital Appropriations Request an intranet application to automate the capital appropriations request process, replacing the paper-based process

Exclusively ERP Project Highlights

Custom extensions or modifications on JD Edwards OneWorld Xe include the following:

- Job Master Inquiry a management tool in JD Edwards, summarizing customer account and project information in credit, sales, finance, engineering, and manufacturing systems, improving documentation and communication between departments; Created a user manual and 25-minute training video for this application using Snaglt, MS Publisher, and MS PowerPoint
- > Production Scheduler fixed sales, purchasing, manufacturing, delivery date issues; linked to Job Master Inquiry and Drafting Input; resulting in fewer problems between Sales and Drafting
- Completed, Not Shipped (CNS) the Finished Goods report every nut & bolt in the plant is processed by this custom JD Edwards report—a critical piece of Vulcraft's month-end closing procedures; the Controller was using five other reports to get this information until CNS was fixed; month-end closing time was reduced by at least 20%; this report became an integral part of testing system changes in JD Edwards
- ➤ Material Resource Planning (MRP) troubleshooting, modifying, and performance-enhancing on this suite of batch applications, to reconcile sales, purchasing, manufacturing, and shipping dates, and reduce execution time & system resource requirements, as this is a resource hog
- ➤ The "Havens" Report a custom management report in JD Edwards, providing in-depth credit analysis of large and/or problematic customer accounts, with two sections—one for the customer, and one for top-level management
- 180-Day Weighted Average a custom financial report in JD Edwards for calculating customer credit scores, based on their last six months of credit history
- > Over 40 Days a custom financial report in JD Edwards for identifying overdue accounts
- ➤ Deck Inventory a custom JD Edwards financial (MRP) report for the Controller and Purchasing Agent, detailing current and projected raw material requirements
- ➤ Fab Schedule the weekly production schedule from which most office activity stems; two specialized versions of this report created for Drafting and Shop Order; ties in to Manufacturing, Customer Service, Job Master, Drafting, and Shop Order Inquiry screens
- Drafting Inquiry added additional fields for tracking approval drawings, and signaling Production Scheduler whether drawings are in-process, out for approval, or back from approval; linked to the Job Master Inquiry and Shop Order Inquiry screens; resulting in providing Production Scheduler with up-to-the minute information for scheduling purposes
- Shop Order Inquiry added additional fields for tracking bills of materials (aka. shop orders) through the engineering design program (outside of JD Edwards); linked to Job Master Inquiry and Drafting Inquiry screens; resulting in much improved traceability and fewer interruptions in Data Entry from Drafting and Shop Order, asking for information
- > Shipping Inquiry a management tool in JD Edwards combining bill of lading, sales, and shipping data for much improved searchability
- ➤ Daily Shipments a key custom JDE financial report used for invoicing, reported tons & dollars sold, tons & dollars shipped, freight amounts and tax-exemption status
- ➤ SO SF Compare a custom JDE application for comparing what was sold to what was built & shipped; used primarily on large jobs to show the dollar amount left to be invoiced
- ➤ Re-price Program a custom JDE application for re-pricing jobs, typically used when design requirements change

Custom Application Highlights

Custom development using MS Excel, Access, VB/VB.Net, SQL, etc. include the following:

- ➤ Internal Audit Manager a custom MS Access database application for managing internal audits of quality and environmental management systems; generates checklists, audit questions, and audit reports
- ➤ Inventory Tracking System a custom MS Excel spreadsheet application to analyze supplier promised & actual delivery dates using data from inventory and cost of quality spreadsheets; results delivered using charts, graphs, and pivot tables
- ➤ NUVU BoM Transfer a stand-alone application using VB.Net & SQL queries to transfer XML data from NUVU bills of materials to the engineering design program, effectively getting NUVU (AutoCAD) to talk to the design program, written in FORTRAN, and still thinks it is running on punch cards; complete with installer and auto-update feature for local and satellite sales offices
- Shipping Route-out Prototype this was a tool to move the current delivery dispatches ("route-out") procedures from paper-based to electronic; prototyped in MS Access and later integrated into J.D. Edwards
- NUVU Installer a collection of shell scripts, HTML, and VB.Net programs to install NUVU on AutoCAD workstations, including network security and administrative shares. All the users had to do to install NUVU was click on a single web-link
- Joist Input Program a front-end to the engineering design program, written in VB5 utilizing a SQL Server database instead of the old flat-files; object model created using Rational Rose; prototyping done in MS Access

Special Projects

- Recovered stolen Internet domain name for a Colorado-based real estate brokerage firm; the investigation tracked the domain records down in Australia, and the owner in Spain; assistance was obtained from the International Trade Administration at the US Department of Commerce
- ➤ Served as Senior Lead Internal Auditor at Vulcraft for six years. Led the team to make the transition from ISO 9001:1994 to ISO 9001:2000, which included leading the team that rewrote the quality manual, and moving the quality manual from paper-based to an interactive on-line system, using MS Internet Information Server (IIS), SharePoint, and FrontPage.
- ➤ Routinely served as corporate liaison with outside auditors of Vulcraft's quality and environmental management systems.

Volunteer Work

Pee Dee Coalition Against Domestic Violence & Sexual Assault, Florence, South Carolina

2005

Volunteer Advocate

- ➤ Participating in Alternatives to Violence (ATV) program
- Conducting in-take interviews for ATV program

Vulcraft News & Views

2000 to 2006

Publisher, Editor, and Contributing Author

- > Writing a regular computer help column for Vulcraft employees
- ➤ Reduced production costs by 97% in only 3 years

Brantford Amiga Users Group

1987 to 1988

Contributing Author

> Researching and writing tutorials for submission

Queensway Baptist Youth Group, Brantford, Ontario

1986 to 1987

Public Relations Coordinator

- Creating promotional materials for fund raising
- Presenting reports at church business meetings

2006

Active Pursuits

- Bitcoin mining and promotion
 Hiking, travel of all sorts
 Developing a strong on-line presence on the internet